<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2022-07-18T14:25:33-05:00</updated><id>https://floridaman7588.me/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Floridaman7588</title><author><name>FloridaMan7588</name></author><entry><title type="html">Guess Who’s Back</title><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/personal/news/website/2022/05/26/guess-whos-back/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guess Who’s Back" /><published>2022-05-26T23:12:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-26T23:12:00-05:00</updated><id>https://floridaman7588.me/personal/news/website/2022/05/26/guess-whos-back</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridaman7588.me/personal/news/website/2022/05/26/guess-whos-back/"><![CDATA[<p>Guess who’s back, back again. Yeah it’s been a while, I’m aware. Remember when I Tweeted saying I would upload a video in a week and then went radio silent for a few months, yeah me neither. I wonder if that’s because it was nearly 7 months ago or if I just have a bad memory. Well yeah I know it’s weird that I come back now but I have my reasons. For example, I’ve been in school the whole time, and though I’m not even in high school, I’ve still been extremely busy. Not only have I been in school, but I’ve had many different personal things going on, not allowing for much time to work on my projects. Now that it’s summer time, I’ve got all the time that I need to work on my projects.</p>

<p>As for those projects, I had decided, during the period of which I had no time, that I will scrap or at least Backburner™ some projects, including my iOS related projects. These include that one Reddit bot I was going to make, my Cydia repository(s), and some other stuff. Now I will continue to work on this website of course, as well as my <a href="https://github.com/floridaman7588/waterfox-flatpak">waterfox-flatpak</a> project, and potentially my ca-server or EasyCA project too. I will continue to be active over my summer break, or at least try to be, and I will continue to update some of my projects.</p>

<p>I did make many changes and updates to this website as well, including fixing mobile support and removing some of those deprecated or archived projects from the navigation bar. You can still access the pages for those projects through the projects tab, but they are most likely unsupported by me. I also added official support for RSS and a proper sitemap file. As for the end user experience, I added pagination and some sharing options as supported by the Alembic Jekyll theme that I use to build this site. I also created a privacy policy, and credited the original author of the theme on the footer. Thats about it in terms of site upgrades, or at least uodates of things that you might notice.</p>

<p>I also intend on streaming quite a bit, and I spent like a day setting up my OBS so I plan not to let that go to waste. You should know where to find me by now, but if you don’t, all my social links can be found at https://fm7588.me/links. I will be streaming on both YouTube and Twitch, and I will stream on multiple YouTube accounts for different reasons (My primary YouTube for code stuff, and my secondary for games). I still need to add my secondary YouTube channel to my link page, but that issue should be resolved by the time this is published.</p>

<p>That’s about it really, I ought to head off to bed now shouldn’t I. It is quite late after all. Well I’m going to sign off now, thanks for reading and have a nice whatever time of day it is where you are!</p>]]></content><author><name>FloridaMan</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="News" /><category term="Website" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guess who’s back, back again. Yeah it’s been a while, I’m aware. Remember when I Tweeted saying I would upload a video in a week and then went radio silent for a few months, yeah me neither. I wonder if that’s because it was nearly 7 months ago or if I just have a bad memory. Well yeah I know it’s weird that I come back now but I have my reasons. For example, I’ve been in school the whole time, and though I’m not even in high school, I’ve still been extremely busy. Not only have I been in school, but I’ve had many different personal things going on, not allowing for much time to work on my projects. Now that it’s summer time, I’ve got all the time that I need to work on my projects. As for those projects, I had decided, during the period of which I had no time, that I will scrap or at least Backburner™ some projects, including my iOS related projects. These include that one Reddit bot I was going to make, my Cydia repository(s), and some other stuff. Now I will continue to work on this website of course, as well as my waterfox-flatpak project, and potentially my ca-server or EasyCA project too. I will continue to be active over my summer break, or at least try to be, and I will continue to update some of my projects. I did make many changes and updates to this website as well, including fixing mobile support and removing some of those deprecated or archived projects from the navigation bar. You can still access the pages for those projects through the projects tab, but they are most likely unsupported by me. I also added official support for RSS and a proper sitemap file. As for the end user experience, I added pagination and some sharing options as supported by the Alembic Jekyll theme that I use to build this site. I also created a privacy policy, and credited the original author of the theme on the footer. Thats about it in terms of site upgrades, or at least uodates of things that you might notice. I also intend on streaming quite a bit, and I spent like a day setting up my OBS so I plan not to let that go to waste. You should know where to find me by now, but if you don’t, all my social links can be found at https://fm7588.me/links. I will be streaming on both YouTube and Twitch, and I will stream on multiple YouTube accounts for different reasons (My primary YouTube for code stuff, and my secondary for games). I still need to add my secondary YouTube channel to my link page, but that issue should be resolved by the time this is published. That’s about it really, I ought to head off to bed now shouldn’t I. It is quite late after all. Well I’m going to sign off now, thanks for reading and have a nice whatever time of day it is where you are!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Backlogged</title><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/personal/2021/11/28/backlogged/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Backlogged" /><published>2021-11-28T21:30:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-28T21:30:00-06:00</updated><id>https://floridaman7588.me/personal/2021/11/28/backlogged</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridaman7588.me/personal/2021/11/28/backlogged/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello yet again! I’ve once again emerged to bring you updates as to what I am doing. You may have noticed very little of anything from me, but that is to be expected with school and a recently acquired position at a local lawn company taking most of my time from me. I have recently been on a school break and was able to get a bit of work in on some projects, such as yet again redefining my home-labs infrastructure and some other fun things soon to come. One such thing is a PiHole HTTP Webhook thing. I don’t know what to call it and I’m also not quite sure Webhook is the correct word, but it’s what I’ll be going with for the foreseeable future. The source for this software is available <a href="https://github.com/floridaman7588/pihole-webhook">here</a>, with documentation available as well.</p>

<p>I am also working on a couple other things, the main one being a project I started a while ago and haven’t introduced yet. This project is….. A Self-Hosted Certificate Authority! I know, I know, you probably already have some solution for HTTPS at home, but this is a simplified version of whatever solution you may run. Currently it is extremely-beta, with barely any functionality besides a couple of core things. I wasn’t planning on introducing it until more was done but who cares really. I will elaborate in further posts and updates but the basic concept is that it issues SSL certificates with a self-signed root certificate. The only difference between my tool and using the CLI or something is that it is managed via a WebUI and not a text interface such as the CLI. It’s just meant to simplify the experience so that beginners and experienced users alike can use SSL on their local services.</p>

<p>There is more for me to talk about but that will probably end up in a post further down the line. It’s getting a bit late for me so I will probably be heading to bed here shortly and won’t continue writing. That’s all from me for now folks, remember to look out for further posts and updates, and I’ll see ya round. Bye!</p>]]></content><author><name>FloridaMan</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello yet again! I’ve once again emerged to bring you updates as to what I am doing. You may have noticed very little of anything from me, but that is to be expected with school and a recently acquired position at a local lawn company taking most of my time from me. I have recently been on a school break and was able to get a bit of work in on some projects, such as yet again redefining my home-labs infrastructure and some other fun things soon to come. One such thing is a PiHole HTTP Webhook thing. I don’t know what to call it and I’m also not quite sure Webhook is the correct word, but it’s what I’ll be going with for the foreseeable future. The source for this software is available here, with documentation available as well. I am also working on a couple other things, the main one being a project I started a while ago and haven’t introduced yet. This project is….. A Self-Hosted Certificate Authority! I know, I know, you probably already have some solution for HTTPS at home, but this is a simplified version of whatever solution you may run. Currently it is extremely-beta, with barely any functionality besides a couple of core things. I wasn’t planning on introducing it until more was done but who cares really. I will elaborate in further posts and updates but the basic concept is that it issues SSL certificates with a self-signed root certificate. The only difference between my tool and using the CLI or something is that it is managed via a WebUI and not a text interface such as the CLI. It’s just meant to simplify the experience so that beginners and experienced users alike can use SSL on their local services. There is more for me to talk about but that will probably end up in a post further down the line. It’s getting a bit late for me so I will probably be heading to bed here shortly and won’t continue writing. That’s all from me for now folks, remember to look out for further posts and updates, and I’ll see ya round. Bye!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Home Assistant Supervised on Docker</title><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/docker/home%20assistant/tutorial/2021/10/03/home-assistant-supervised/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home Assistant Supervised on Docker" /><published>2021-10-03T00:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-03T00:30:00-05:00</updated><id>https://floridaman7588.me/docker/home%20assistant/tutorial/2021/10/03/home-assistant-supervised</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridaman7588.me/docker/home%20assistant/tutorial/2021/10/03/home-assistant-supervised/"><![CDATA[<p>Hey, it’s me again! I’m actually doing something too. Right now the thing that I’m doing is a write-up for a YouTube video that I made like half a year ago.
Yeah. Let’s get started.</p>

<h2 id="before-we-get-started">Before we get started</h2>

<p>Before we get started I need to clarify that my video uses a now outdated script for deploying Home Assistant Supervised, so in this write-up we will be using
the updated version. I also need to say that this tutorial was originally made on a VMware amd64 virtual machine, but it should work on a bare metal host. Now the lsdt thing I have to say is that this install script is for Debian 10 buster but I believe it should work on other flavours of linux as well. Please correct me if I’m wrong. Alright let’s get started now.</p>

<h2 id="step-1-installing-dependencies">Step 1, installing dependencies</h2>

<p>This tutorial is assuming that you are runnng Debian 10 Buster (and derivatives) or Debian 11 Bullseye (and derivatives). The first thing we need to do is update
our apt package lists so that we can download everything properly. We can do this by running</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo apt update</code></p>

<p>and then running</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo apt upgrade -y</code></p>

<p>to update any packages that need to be. Then we are going to install our dependencies with</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo apt install -y software-properties-common apparmor-utils apt-transport-https ca-certificates curl dbus jq network-manager</code></p>

<p>This adds the necessary software to our system for Docker to properley run our containers. We also need to disable the ModemManager service for everything to work properly. We can do this by running</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo systemctl disable ModemManager</code></p>

<p>and stop it by running</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo systemctl stop ModemManager</code></p>

<h3 id="step-11-installing-docker">Step 1.1, Installing Docker</h3>

<p>To install Docker, we will downlod and run the convenience script from the Docker website by running</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">curl -fsSL get.docker.com | sudo sh</code></p>

<p>this should completley download and install docker without much of any use interaction.</p>

<h2 id="step-2-install-home-assistant">Step 2, Install Home Assistant</h2>

<p>To install Home Assistant we are going to simply clone and run the Home Assistant Supervised install script from GitHub by running</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">curl -Lo installer.sh https://raw.githubusercontent.com/home-assistant/supervised-installer/master/installer.sh</code></p>

<p>and running the script simple by using</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo bash installer.sh</code></p>

<p>and that should do it. Just sit back and let the installer do it’s thing.</p>

<h2 id="step-3-onboarding">Step 3, Onboarding</h2>

<p>At this point Home Assitant should be installed and the install script should have spit out an ip for you to connect to. For instance my video shows 192.168.81.128 at port 8123. Since I was using a GUI I was just able to connect to localhost instead, but you are probably installing in a headless environment so you NEED to connect to your devices hostname/local ip address. At this point you should see something like this: <img src="/assets/images/docker/home-assistant-onboarding.png" alt="home-assistant-onboarding.png" title="home-assistant-onboarding.png" /></p>

<p>Once your here, your golden. You can complete the setup by following the instructions and you’ll have it completley set up.</p>

<h2 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping Up</h2>

<p>Well, congratulations! You’ve succesfully deployed an entire network of Docker container for running your smart home. Great job! This was a rather simple process but when I was first starting out these kind of articles were huge helps, so I hope this one will help you. Have a good rest of your day/night/whatever, and goodbye!</p>]]></content><author><name>FloridaMan</name></author><category term="Docker" /><category term="Home Assistant" /><category term="Tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey, it’s me again! I’m actually doing something too. Right now the thing that I’m doing is a write-up for a YouTube video that I made like half a year ago. Yeah. Let’s get started. Before we get started Before we get started I need to clarify that my video uses a now outdated script for deploying Home Assistant Supervised, so in this write-up we will be using the updated version. I also need to say that this tutorial was originally made on a VMware amd64 virtual machine, but it should work on a bare metal host. Now the lsdt thing I have to say is that this install script is for Debian 10 buster but I believe it should work on other flavours of linux as well. Please correct me if I’m wrong. Alright let’s get started now. Step 1, installing dependencies This tutorial is assuming that you are runnng Debian 10 Buster (and derivatives) or Debian 11 Bullseye (and derivatives). The first thing we need to do is update our apt package lists so that we can download everything properly. We can do this by running sudo apt update and then running sudo apt upgrade -y to update any packages that need to be. Then we are going to install our dependencies with sudo apt install -y software-properties-common apparmor-utils apt-transport-https ca-certificates curl dbus jq network-manager This adds the necessary software to our system for Docker to properley run our containers. We also need to disable the ModemManager service for everything to work properly. We can do this by running sudo systemctl disable ModemManager and stop it by running sudo systemctl stop ModemManager Step 1.1, Installing Docker To install Docker, we will downlod and run the convenience script from the Docker website by running curl -fsSL get.docker.com | sudo sh this should completley download and install docker without much of any use interaction. Step 2, Install Home Assistant To install Home Assistant we are going to simply clone and run the Home Assistant Supervised install script from GitHub by running curl -Lo installer.sh https://raw.githubusercontent.com/home-assistant/supervised-installer/master/installer.sh and running the script simple by using sudo bash installer.sh and that should do it. Just sit back and let the installer do it’s thing. Step 3, Onboarding At this point Home Assitant should be installed and the install script should have spit out an ip for you to connect to. For instance my video shows 192.168.81.128 at port 8123. Since I was using a GUI I was just able to connect to localhost instead, but you are probably installing in a headless environment so you NEED to connect to your devices hostname/local ip address. At this point you should see something like this: Once your here, your golden. You can complete the setup by following the instructions and you’ll have it completley set up. Wrapping Up Well, congratulations! You’ve succesfully deployed an entire network of Docker container for running your smart home. Great job! This was a rather simple process but when I was first starting out these kind of articles were huge helps, so I hope this one will help you. Have a good rest of your day/night/whatever, and goodbye!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello Again</title><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/news/personal/2021/10/02/hello-again/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello Again" /><published>2021-10-02T00:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:30:00-05:00</updated><id>https://floridaman7588.me/news/personal/2021/10/02/hello-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridaman7588.me/news/personal/2021/10/02/hello-again/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, it’s been a while. I’ve been busy with school and everything but I’m sure chugging along here. I was busy working with some docker compose scripts and such a while back working with my smart home but otherwise I haven’t been doing much. I’ve tried to get some work done on the docker things and my (hopefully) coming soon reddit bot, but I just haven’t had much time. You can try to expect more from me, but you never know. The website is pretty much finished, I’ve only got a few housekeeping things to work on (commenting, RSS, EMail feed, etc.) so there probably won’t be much else to see for a while. I will try and get at least the bungeecord container updated for the latest version of Minecraft &amp; Bungeecord, but that’s probably about it for a while. I am getting pretty tired, so I think I’m going to sign off for now. Have a good day/night/whatever and goodbye!</p>]]></content><author><name>FloridaMan</name></author><category term="News" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, it’s been a while. I’ve been busy with school and everything but I’m sure chugging along here. I was busy working with some docker compose scripts and such a while back working with my smart home but otherwise I haven’t been doing much. I’ve tried to get some work done on the docker things and my (hopefully) coming soon reddit bot, but I just haven’t had much time. You can try to expect more from me, but you never know. The website is pretty much finished, I’ve only got a few housekeeping things to work on (commenting, RSS, EMail feed, etc.) so there probably won’t be much else to see for a while. I will try and get at least the bungeecord container updated for the latest version of Minecraft &amp; Bungeecord, but that’s probably about it for a while. I am getting pretty tired, so I think I’m going to sign off for now. Have a good day/night/whatever and goodbye!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Progress</title><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/09/07/progress/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Progress" /><published>2021-09-07T18:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-07T18:30:00-05:00</updated><id>https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/09/07/progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/09/07/progress/"><![CDATA[<p>Hey, long time no see, or write I guess. Well, I’m working on the website again. This is just a progress post, and as you can see a lot of progress has been made. I have started school so things may not be as frequent as I’d like them to be but it’s really whatever. AFAIK, my schedule should allow for at least an hour of work each day, but that may be limited by other factors(eg. family whatevers or having a social life). I do have some other projects that I’m working on, so this website isn’t the number 1 priority (btw you can check out those other projects <a href="https://floridaman7588.me/projects">here</a>).</p>]]></content><author><name>FloridaMan</name></author><category term="News" /><category term="Website" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey, long time no see, or write I guess. Well, I’m working on the website again. This is just a progress post, and as you can see a lot of progress has been made. I have started school so things may not be as frequent as I’d like them to be but it’s really whatever. AFAIK, my schedule should allow for at least an hour of work each day, but that may be limited by other factors(eg. family whatevers or having a social life). I do have some other projects that I’m working on, so this website isn’t the number 1 priority (btw you can check out those other projects here).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website Updates</title><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/07/22/website-updates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website Updates" /><published>2021-07-22T02:24:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-07-22T02:24:00-05:00</updated><id>https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/07/22/website-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/07/22/website-updates/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi! You may have noticied nothing, the website still isn’t avaliable on the open web yet. That means there is a very slim chance that you are reading this unless I know you personally. If you are reading this, cool. I’ve been working on my website here and I’ve added a couple pages, as well as some other special little things around the place. You may notice the ‘Cydia’ and ‘AltStore Source’ tabs at the top appearing. Those are pretty self-explanatory to most people that my audience consists of. If you don’t understand what they are, clicking on them probably won’t help either unfortunatley. The are what they say they are. But anyways anyways, these new pages aren’t just pages. They allow direct access to what each one states that it might be. Have a look, and a few clicks around. You might find yourself adding my AltSource through a link or two (Hint, Hint). Yeah that’s really about it, I’m hoping to purchase a domain name soon so that this website will be nice and proper. Once that happens this site will probably be near completion anyways. Check back soon for more details and updates, hope to see you.</p>]]></content><author><name>FloridaMan</name></author><category term="News" /><category term="Website" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi! You may have noticied nothing, the website still isn’t avaliable on the open web yet. That means there is a very slim chance that you are reading this unless I know you personally. If you are reading this, cool. I’ve been working on my website here and I’ve added a couple pages, as well as some other special little things around the place. You may notice the ‘Cydia’ and ‘AltStore Source’ tabs at the top appearing. Those are pretty self-explanatory to most people that my audience consists of. If you don’t understand what they are, clicking on them probably won’t help either unfortunatley. The are what they say they are. But anyways anyways, these new pages aren’t just pages. They allow direct access to what each one states that it might be. Have a look, and a few clicks around. You might find yourself adding my AltSource through a link or two (Hint, Hint). Yeah that’s really about it, I’m hoping to purchase a domain name soon so that this website will be nice and proper. Once that happens this site will probably be near completion anyways. Check back soon for more details and updates, hope to see you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Website</title><link href="https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/06/28/new-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Website" /><published>2021-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/06/28/new-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridaman7588.me/news/website/2021/06/28/new-website/"><![CDATA[<p>Finally, a new website that isn’t totally stolen from someone else. Though I am kind of cheating as I’m using Jekyll to make this. Anyways, let’s talk about this 
here new website. As I’ve stated, I am using Jekyll to make this site so It’s a bit easier on me. This website is going to be a general blogging/tutorial/whatever 
website for me to post about my projects and other things I do in my spare time.</p>

<p>I am doing other things in my time currently (ex. spending time with the other humans), but I will be working on more projects sooner or later. I haven’t
published a new YouTube video lately so I intend on doing some more of those eventually. I plan on learning some more programming languages over the summer period. I will be working on C and Swift in particualr, but I may change my mind.</p>

<p>Some projects I’ve been working on lately are</p>
<ol>
  <li>This website</li>
  <li>Learning Ansible</li>
  <li>Working on my Docker skills</li>
  <li>Learning the aforementioned launguages (C and Swift)</li>
</ol>

<p>So you can expect more to come from me in relation to these things. I am attemping to whip up an Ansible playbook to install Docker on any computer so look forward to that.</p>

<p>Anyways, I’ve got some more work to do here so I am going to end this blog post update thing here. See y’all later.</p>]]></content><author><name>FloridaMan</name></author><category term="News" /><category term="Website" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Finally, a new website that isn’t totally stolen from someone else. Though I am kind of cheating as I’m using Jekyll to make this. Anyways, let’s talk about this here new website. As I’ve stated, I am using Jekyll to make this site so It’s a bit easier on me. This website is going to be a general blogging/tutorial/whatever website for me to post about my projects and other things I do in my spare time. I am doing other things in my time currently (ex. spending time with the other humans), but I will be working on more projects sooner or later. I haven’t published a new YouTube video lately so I intend on doing some more of those eventually. I plan on learning some more programming languages over the summer period. I will be working on C and Swift in particualr, but I may change my mind. Some projects I’ve been working on lately are This website Learning Ansible Working on my Docker skills Learning the aforementioned launguages (C and Swift) So you can expect more to come from me in relation to these things. I am attemping to whip up an Ansible playbook to install Docker on any computer so look forward to that. Anyways, I’ve got some more work to do here so I am going to end this blog post update thing here. See y’all later.]]></summary></entry></feed>